Paul Kane

Front-end Developer at Apple

Summary

"It's more than building something. It's delivering an experience."

I specialize in front-end web development, carefully crafting and preserving design integrity, and delivering on the promise of interactivity and user experience.

I love working with clients directly, or as part of a larger team to create new solutions. I've been a part of some incredible projects and I approach each one as an opportunity to learn something new.

My undergraduate studies were in broadcast journalism. This includes writing, producing, and editing for radio/television and interactive media. My ability to adapt, work under deadlines or constant pressure, and most importantly, communicate effectively stems from this education.

Core languages: XHTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

Active proficiency with:

Backbone, Underscore, Git, jQuery, SASS, Angular

Always open to discussing new technologies and practices.

Experience

Front-end Developer at Apple

November 2015 - Present

Creative Developer at AKQA

December 2014 - October 2015 (10 months)

Web application development for ground-breaking client initiatives. Focus on front-end presentation and interaction, as well as framework level class creation and manipulation.

Web Design and Development

March 2010 - January 2015 (4 years 10 months)

I offer individualized professional web services, including website design, development, CMS implementation, site and search optimization, and content writing and editing.

My specialty is front-end design and development, meaning user experience and interaction. However, I can provide advice and consultation regarding a wide array of web strategies and technologies.

Front-End Developer / Designer at Gannett

January 2012 - December 2014 (2 years 11 months)

Development of web design initiatives and applications for USATODAY.COM and affiliate websites.

Interaction across departments for the successful contribution of design, interaction planning and execution.

Collaboration on design processes and design of web applications and related materials.

Web Developer at Cvent

May 2010 - January 2012 (1 year 8 months)

Website Development, including static HTML and CSS coding for corporate marketing site and subdomains.

JavaScript coding, from scratch and in deployment of frameworks such as jQuery for wide array of applications.

Issue tracking, site maintenance, and optimization across multiple platforms.

Collaboration with teams in HQ and India branch for development and large scale site changes and deployment.

Developer, Support

March 2009 - May 2010 (1 year 2 months)

Website design and development, including creative analysis, coding, content management, and open source integration.

Client relations, involving design planning, issue troubleshooting, and full office training for content management systems.

Intern

August 2008 - December 2008 (4 months)

Assisted with Audio/Visual equipment set-up and break-down during Professional broadcasts.

Logged and managed game footage for video archival and editing.

Liaison for broadcast managers and technicians.

Intern

May 2008 - August 2008 (3 months)

Coordinated with Sports Producer in the studio and field for daily production of broadcasts.

Authored team pages for Sports section of website.

Assisted with creation of segments for professional broadcasts.

Event Technician

August 2005 - May 2006 (9 months)

Responsible for the set-up, operation, and breakdown of audio/visual equipment for concerts, presentations, films, shows, and other events.

Coordinated with organizations to successfully execute events for committees and their guests.

Managed and oversaw large inventory of high-end electronics.

Education

University of Central Florida

B.A., Communication, 2006 - 2008

University of Central Florida

Minor, Information Technology, 2006 - 2008

Paul Kane

Front-end Developer at Apple



Contact Paul on LinkedIn